James A. Pike Papers
James A. Pike Papers
- Professional records
  - Resignation as Bishop of California, 1966-1969
    - Transcript of news conference by Bishops Myers and Hines, Jan 1967 (Box 82)
- Recordings
  - Audio, formats include reel tapes and phonograph records
    - #2 Lecture by Mr. R.P. Beesley "[Trinitarian] Concepts", 04/28/1965; pike_ja_085; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - 4th of the Series of [James A Pike] with Fred Myers: Curses of Modern Man: An Age of Anxiety, 00/00/1967; pike_ja_091; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Art of Living #1, 07/05/0000; pike_ja_078; 1 reel tape, 1/4", running time 13:30 (Oversize 11)
    - Art of Living #2, pike_ja_079; 1 reel tape, 1/4", running time 13:30 (Oversize 11)
    - Art of Living #3, pike_ja_080; 1 reel tape, 1/4", running time 13:30 (Oversize 11)
    - Assignment: People, 11/00/1965; pike_ja_117; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Benjamin H. Swig Testimonial Dinner (Sides 1 and 4), 11/20/1963; pike_ja_118; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Benjamin H. Swig Testimonial Dinner (Sides 2 and 3), 11/20/1963; pike_ja_119; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Betty Furness Show, 02/23/1961; pike_ja_082; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Bishop James A Pike at Florida Presbyterian College, 09/19/1966; pike_ja_088; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 1 7/8 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Bishop Pike, pike_ja_099; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Bishop Pike [at] All Saints, Nov. 1, 1964; pike_ja_009; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Bishop Pike Discussion Part 1 (Reel 1 Side 2) University Presbyterian Church Directories Section ‘67 Dr. Martin Marty, pike_ja_066; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 10)
    - Bishop Pike [in] New York, New York, April 8th 1968; pike_ja_023; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 9)
    - "Bishop Pike Question and Answer Period Part 1 and 2", 10/13/1967; 10/14/1967,; 10/15/1967; 13th Annual BANFF Conference United Church Men "Pike Speaks" (Sides 5 and 6); pike_ja_116; 1 disc, 1/4", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Blake-Pike Proposal [Cuecounter], 01/24/1965; pike_ja_015; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Bos For Dub HR 2, pike_ja_061; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - Christ Church Cathedral, St. Louis, Oct 11,1964; pike_ja_005; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Christ Church Cathedral, St. Louis, Oct 11, 1964; pike_ja_006; Sermon at 11 AM service; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - Church World News, Faith of our Fathers, 10/18/1964; pike_ja_008; 1 reel tape, 7 1/2 ips, running time 28:00 (Oversize 9)
    - Commentary #1, 01/18/1968; pike_ja_037; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:17 (Oversize 9)
    - Commentary #2, 02/01/1968; pike_ja_038; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:50 (Oversize 9)
    - Commentary #3, 02/20/1968; pike_ja_039; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 17:13 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #4, 02/29/1968; pike_ja_040; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 15:09 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #5, 03/08/1968; pike_ja_041; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 19:55 (Oversize 10)
    - Community #6, 03/00/1968; pike_ja_042; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:34 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #7, 04/00/1968; pike_ja_043; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:56 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #8, 04/25/1968; pike_ja_044; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:51 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #9, 05/09/1968; pike_ja_045; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:35 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #10, 05/09/1698; pike_ja_046; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:45 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #11, 05/17/1968; pike_ja_047; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:12 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #12, 05/17/1968; pike_ja_048; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 14:24 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #13, 07/02/1968; pike_ja_049; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 14:40 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #14, 07/23/1968; pike_ja_050; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 14:13 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #15, 08/01/1968; pike_ja_051; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 14:29 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #16, 08/15/1968; pike_ja_052; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 14:21 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #17, 09/05/1968; pike_ja_053; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:48 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #18, 09/12/1968; pike_ja_054; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:56 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #19, 10/03/1968; pike_ja_055; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 13:29 (Oversize 10)
    - Commentary #20, 10/10/1968; pike_ja_056; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 14:20 (Oversize 10)
    - Community in Crisis #1 Alcoholism; Community in Crisis #2 Family Planning, pike_ja_011; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 104:05 (Oversize 9)
    - Community in Crisis #3 Aging; Community in Crisis #4 Mental Retardation, 03/31/1965; pike_ja_012; 1 reel tape, 1/4", running time 126:10 (Oversize 9)
    - Community in Crisis #5 Poverty; Community in Crisis #6 The Community and the Church, pike_ja_013; 1 reel tape, 1/4", running time 121:55 (Oversize 9)
    - Dialogue: Situation Ethics, recorded 02/17/1967; broadcast 03/07/1967,; 03/11/1967; pike_ja_004; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 120:00 (Oversize 9)
    - Diocesan Convention, Jan 1969; pike_ja_094; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Directors Section ‘67 Discussion Part 2; Dr. Robert Lynn Reel 2, pike_ja_067; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 10)
    - Ellen Terry and Dr. Cosmo Lang, Late Archbishop of Canterbury, pike_ja_030; Medium Mr. Leslie Flint; Sitters Mrs. Betty Greene; Mr. S.G Woods; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Eternal Life and Social Action Now Foerster Lecture, 1964; pike_ja_033; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 71:35 (Oversize 9)
    - The Ever-changing, Multi-lingual, Transcendental, Two-Ton Mustard Seed...the Program of Better Living through the Chemistry of Love, 12/31/1967; pike_ja_027; 1 reel tape, 1/4", running time 27:30 (Oversize 9)
    - Face the Future "Promos"; Face the Future Program 1 "Birthrate"(Disc 1 of 7), 1960; pike_ja_120; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Face the Future Program 2 "Political Science"; Face the Future Program 3 "Law" (Disc 2 of 7), 1960; pike_ja_121; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Face the Future Program 4 "Theology"; Face the Future Program 5 "Machined Mentality" (Disc 3 of 7), 1960; pike_ja_122; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Face the Future Program 6 "Sustenance"; Face the Future Program 7 "Superstition" (Disc 4 of 7), 1960; pike_ja_123; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Face the Future Program 8 "Primordial Power"; Face the Future Program 9 "Communications" (Disc 5 of 7), 1960; pike_ja_124; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Face the Future Program 10 "Medicine"; Face the Future Program 11 "Vehicle Engineering" (Disc 6 of 7), 1960; pike_ja_125; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Face the Future Program 12 "Gravity"; Face the Future Program 13 "Security" (Disc 7 of 7), 1960; pike_ja_126; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - "Fargo" interview with "Al Watson" of "Club Exotique", in reality Albert West of 848 1/2 39th Street, Sacramento; pike_ja_100; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 1 7/8 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Fargo transmitter interview with "Kelly" of ISARE, 03/22/1963; pike_ja_101; "Kelly" is Chester Roberts of San Francisco; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 1 7/8 ips (Oversize 11)
    - "Fewer Beliefs - More Beliefs" and "Varieties of Religious Experience", 10/13/1967; 10/14/1967,; 10/15/1967; 13th Annual BANFF Conference United Church Men "Pike Speaks" (Sides 1 and 2); pike_ja_114; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Garrin Lecture, pike_ja_001; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - George Hamilton Coombs "Spotlight on New York" (Sides 1 and 3), 07/17/1953; pike_ja_112; 1 disc, 16", 33 1/3 rpm
    - George Hamilton Coombs "Spotlight on New York" (Side 2), 07/17/1953; pike_ja_113; 1 disc, 16", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Ghosts in the [LaSeretery?] translated from Corriere Della Sera by EMB, pike_ja_105; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - The Good Life (#201), pike_ja_095; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 11)
    - The Good Life (Reel #207), pike_ja_096; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Grace Cathedral Prayer and Unity Seminar #1 Dillenberger and Blake (1 of 2), 01/24/1965; pike_ja_014; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 56:35 (Oversize 9)
    - Grace Cathedral Christian Unity Seminar #2 "On Christian Unity" (1 of 2), 01/25/1965; pike_ja_016; Tape says reel 1 of 2 but lists running time as 110:00; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Grace Cathedral Christian Unity Seminar #2 "On Christian Unity" (2 of 2), 01/25/1965; pike_ja_017; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Grace Cathedral Christian Unity Panel Discussion (1 of 2), 01/25/1965; pike_ja_018; overall time for the panel discussion is 2:11:00; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Grace Cathedral Christian Unity Panel Discussion (2 of 2), 01/25/1965; pike_ja_019; Overall time for the panel discussion is 2:11:00; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Grace Cathedral Promo 11.23-11.27, pike_ja_108; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Gustavus Adolphus College St. Peter, Minnesota, 01/23/1967; pike_ja_020; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - Hans Holzer interview with James Pike, 04/08/1968; pike_ja_092; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Hans Holzer, Albert, Ethel, et al., 04/08/1968; pike_ja_093; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - House of Bishop 1966; Bishop Pike Affair (Bishop Dun’s Title) (#1), 00/00/1966; pike_ja_031; possibly continued on pike_ja_032; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - Joe Pyne Show, pike_ja_110; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 1 7/8 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Man under Stress Tape 4, 11/16/1963; pike_ja_003; 9:00 AM Sat. [Ravdin] Speech; Ends with Applz [applause?]; 1 reel tape, 1/4", running time 32:40 (Oversize 9)
    - McIntire, 02/20/1967; pike_ja_089; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Mitchell Folk Mass of Church of the Resurrection, 05/02/1965; pike_ja_010; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 9)
    - The National Council on Alcoholism: "Partners in Progress", pike_ja_058; Address The Right Reverend Rev. James A. Pike, J.S.A., S.T.D. Bishop of the Episcopal Diocese of Calif[ornia].; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 10)
    - New Looks at Christian Origins (1 of 3), pike_ja_035; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 180:00 (Oversize 9)
    - New Looks at Christian Origins (2 of 3), pike_ja_034; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 120:00 (Oversize 9)
    - New Looks at Christian Origins (3 of 3), pike_ja_062; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - Bishop Pike and Pennsylvania State University, pike_ja_036; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - The New Morality: Trends in Modern Theology, 05/12/1957; pike_ja_022; Lecture at Central Washington State College, Ellensburg, Washington; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 90:00 (Oversize 9)
    - Open Mind (1 of 2), 03/08/1967; pike_ja_025; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - Open Mind (2 of 2), 03/08/1967; pike_ja_026; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - "The Other Side", Holzer-Werimer special film on [James A Pike] psychic expers. APPROVAL COPY; pike_ja_106; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Pennsylvania State University (3 of 3), pike_ja_063; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - Pennsylvania State University (2 of 3), pike_ja_064; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - Piano, 03/08/1968; pike_ja_057; 1 disc, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips, running time 08:11 (Oversize 10)
    - Pike M.S., 12/04/1966; pike_ja_007; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - Pike Farewell Sermon, pike_ja_021; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips, running time 45:00 (Oversize 9)
    - Pike News Conference at St. Francis, pike_ja_102; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Reply by Bishop Pike (#2), 10/25/1966; pike_ja_032; possibly a continuation of pike_ja_031; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - St. Louis Sermon (2 of 2), pike_ja_081; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Scarsdale Public Schools (1 of 2), pike_ja_098; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Scarsdale Public Schools (2 of 2), pike_ja_097; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Sermon by Bishop James Pike at St. Andrews Episcopal Church,Rochester, NY, May 21, 1967; pike_ja_090; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Service for the Consecration of the very reverend James Albert Pike as Bishop Coadjutor of California [Japanese Title], June 29th 1957; pike_ja_002; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - Speech at Marietta College, 04/05/1967; pike_ja_029; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 9)
    - "Survival of the Human Personality" and Jack Sibley, Chairman, Canadian Committee Operation Crossroads Africa; Bob Burrows "New Tools for Urban Missions", 10/13/1967; 10/14/1967,; 10/15/1967; 13th Annual BANFF Conference United Church Men "Pike Speaks" (Sides 3 and 4); pike_ja_115; 1 disc, 12", 33 1/3 rpm
    - Union through Sound (and Silence) Mr. R.P. Beesley in Claxton Hall, Lecture #3, 04/27/1966; pike_ja_087; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Viewpoint (Reel 188), 12/23/1961; 12/24/1961; pike_ja_083; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips (Oversize 11)
    - Viewpoint (Reel 312), 05/22/1964; pike_ja_084; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 11)
    - "Why Christ?" Talk to Youth of Luth[eran] Church in Detroit, 1965; pike_ja_086; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - Wedding of Michael and Ann Rowe (Reel 1), 01/04/1964; pike_ja_103; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 11)
    - WSA Symposium (2 of 2), 02/16/1967; pike_ja_024; Bishop Pike talk of Thursday, February 16, 1967; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - WSA Symposium (1 of 2), February 16, 1967; pike_ja_028; Bishop Pike talk; 1 reel tape, 1/4", 3 3/4 ips (Oversize 9)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #1], pike_ja_059; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #2], pike_ja_060; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #3], pike_ja_065; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #4], pike_ja_068; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #5], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_069; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #6], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_070; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #7], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_071; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #8], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_072; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #9], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_073; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #10], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_074; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #11], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_075; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #12], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_076; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 10)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #13], Riverside Radio (WRVR) New York, NY, pike_ja_077; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike Reel #14] Mac 8-17, pike_ja_104; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - [Untitled James A. Pike #15], pike_ja_107; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - [Unidentified James A. Pike #16], pike_ja_109; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
    - [Unidentified James A. Pike #17], pike_ja_111; 1 reel tape, 1/4" (Oversize 11)
  - Video, formats include film, reel videotape, and videocassettes
    - 1954 Nazareth Travelog, pike_ja_127; Film: 16mm b/w
    - "At Home With Dean Pike," Winters Prods., pike_ja_128; Film: 16mm b/w
    - [Caravan Film: Tiberius And The Sea of Galilee] "Reel (1)", damaged, separated into three pieces; pike_ja_129; Film: 16mm b/w
    - Face The Nation - Right Reverend James A. Pike, Bishop Of The Episcopal Diocese Of California, CBS Television Network, 12/12/1960; pike_ja_131; Film: 16mm b/w
    - Frontiers of Faith Print No. 3, NBC, New York, N.Y., 02/27/1955; pike_ja_133; Film: 16mm b/w
    - Frontiers of Faith #7, NBC, New York, N.Y., 06/24/1956; pike_ja_134; Film: 16mm b/w
    - "Houston Special," KHOU TV Channel 11 CBS, Houston, Texas, 03/26/1961; includes photocopy of outside of original box with shipping label; pike_ja_130; 2 inch videotape: Quad (Box 111)
    - "In Search Of... Bishop Pike", 02/15/1982; pike_ja_136; Betacam (Box 110)
    - Kron: "Assignment Four," "Man With A New Mission", Leo Diner Films, Inc., San Francisco, CA, pike_ja_135; Film: 16mm color
    - Pike sermon, pike_ja_132; Film: 16mm b/w
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Abortion: The Freedom To Be Responsible" Medical World, Jan 1966; typescript copy revised (Box 82)
    - "Ad Hoc Conscientious Objection and the First Amendment" Center Magazine, 1969; drafts A-E typescripts, some reproductions, some with revisions; 5 folders (Box 82)
    - "The Anatomy of A Judgment", draft (incomplete), typescript copy (Box 82)
    - "The Anatomy of Independence", typescript revised (Box 82)
    - "The Art of Being Conservative: What to Conserve, What to Throw Away" Vogue, Jan 1952 (Box 82)
    - "Anglican Christianity", published material (Box 82)
    - "Anxiety and Beyond" Pastoral Psychology, Sep 1953; published material (Box 82)
    - "Birth Control and the Christian" (excerpts from If You Marry Outside Your Faith), published material (Box 82)
    - "Bishop Pike Answers Criticisms of California Customary" The Witness, Sep 1959; published material (Box 82)
    - "Bishop Pike Hails A 'Day of Victory'", published material (Box 82)
    - "Bishop Pike on ESP" Jubilee, Feb 1968; published material (Box 82)
    - "A Bishop Writes About Teen-agers and Sex" Woman's Day (Australia), Dec 1965; published material (Box 82)
    - "Catholic-Protestant Birth Control Views" New York Herald-Tribune, published material reproduction (Box 82)
    - "The Christian and Birth Control", Oct 1952; confidential draft, typescript reproduction (Box 82)
    - "Christianity and the Self: Religion and Depth Psychology" Alumni Bulletin: Bangor Theological Seminary, Apr 1957; published material (Box 82)
    - "Christianity, Democracy and Education", 1960; typescript revised (Box 83)
    - "Christianity Is In Retreat" Look, Dec 1960; drafts A-C (incomplete), typescripts and typescript copies, with revisions; published material; 4 folders (Box 83)
    - "A Christian Looks At Israel" Jewish Heritage, Fall 1958; printed material (Box 83)
    - "The Church and the Public Schools, Part I" The Southern Churchman, Aug 1951; published material (Box 83)
    - "The Church and the Public Schools, Part III" The Southern Churchman, Sep 1951; published material (Box 83)
    - "The Church and Women", typescript reproduction revised (Box 83)
    - "Church Unity: 'Summit' and 'Local Break-throughs,'" Church of England Newspaper, Jun 1961; draft A, typescript revised; draft B, typescript copy; published material; 3 folders (Box 83)
    - "The Churches" Center Magazine, Oct-Nov 1967; published material (Box 83)
    - "Clergy-Organist Relationships -- Law or Tact?" American Guild of Organists Quarterly, Jul 1958; typescript copy revised, published material; 2 folders (Box 83)
    - "The Colleges--Diagnosis and Prescription" Living Church, vol. CXIX, no. 19, 1949; typescript copy revised; published material; 2 folders (Box 83)
    - "Communion--Open or Closed?" Living Church, Aug 1959; published material (Box 83)
    - "Communities Are Very Important" Optimist Magazine, 1964; typescript revised (Box 83)
    - "Crutches for the Spirit" Parade, Dec 1957; typescript copy revised (Box 83)
    - "Democracy: the Right to be Different" Living Church, May 1952; published material (Box 83)
    - "Dear Jim" "Dear Carroll" Living Church, Dec 1964; published material (Box 83)
    - "A Declining Church Must Listen" Episcopalian, Jul 1967; published material (Box 83)
    - "Doesn't Evil Disprove God?" with John Krumm, Episcopal Churchnews, Mar 1954; published material (Box 83)
    - "Educators Assault Democracy in the Name of Democracy" Episcopal Churchnews, May 1952; published material (Box 83)
    - "The Effectiveness of the Church", 1961; typescript copy (Box 83)
    - "The Episcopal Church: Catholic, Protestant, and Liberal" The Church Militant, Sep 1952; typescript copy revised; published material; 3 folders (Box 83)
    - "Naturaleza de la Iglesia Epicopal" Heraldo Episcopal, 1953; Spanish translation of "The Episcopal Church: Catholic, Protestant, and Liberal"; published material (Box 83)
    - "The Ethics Beyond Legal Ethics", 1961; printed material (Box 83)
    - "The Ethics of Family Planning, " Occidental College American Assembly Final Report on The Population Dilemma: Implications for Policy and Action, 1963; printed material (Box 83)
    - "Fair Taxation for the Churches", 1967?; research material
      - Research material, typescript, typescript copy, holo, published material repro, printed material; 3 folders (Box 83)
      - Outline, typescript copy annotated (Box 83)
      - Drafts, A, typescript revised; B, typescript copy revised; 2 folders (Box 83)
    - "Four Cases in the New Morality" Ladies' Home Journal, May 1967; published material annotated (Box 83)
    - "Freud's Influence on Modern Religion" Menninger School of Psychiatry, Think, Mar 1960; printed material, published material; 2 folders (Box 83)
    - "The Functions of the Cathedral" Bulletin of the Diocese of New York, Mar 1952; published material (Box 83)
    - "A God-Shaped Blank in Man's Heart" Vogue, Jul 1950; published material (Box 83)
    - "Great Convictions Revived" The New-Church Messenger, Oct 1955; published material (Box 83)
    - "Happiness Without Pills" Pageant, Apr 1958; published material (Box 83)
    - "Has Pragmatism Undermined Basic Values in Education?" Teachers College Record, Oct 1954; published material (Box 83)
    - "Has The Supreme Court Outlawed Religious Observance in the Schools?", Oct 1962; drafts A and B, typescript copies with revisions; published material; 3 folders (Box 83)
    - "Heretic, I'm Not" Los Angeles FM and Fine Arts, Jan 1967; published material (Box 83)
    - "Hints" Kappa Alpha Journal, May 1936; printed material (Box 83)
    - "How To Deal With Fear" Witness, Nov 1953; published material (Box 83)
    - "How To Face Life" Woman's Day, Jul 1957; published material (Box 83)
    - "How to Handle a Sense of Guilt" Presbyterian Life, Mar 1955; published material (Box 83)
    - "How To Meet Temptation" San Francisco Call-Bulletin, May 1958; published material (Box 83)
    - "How To Sleep" San Francisco Call-Bulletin, May 1958; published material (Box 84)
    - "How To Love People You Don't Like" Woman's Day, Aug 1957; published material (Box 84)
    - "How To Pray" Pageant, Feb; Reader's Digest, May 1958; published material (Box 84)
    - "How To Stay Married" Woman's Day, Sep 1957; published material (Box 84)
    - "Huckstering God is Dangerous" Coronet, Jul 1957; typescript copy revised; published material; 2 folders (Box 84)
    - "I Object To Juke-Box Religion" This Week, Nov 1956; typescript copy revised; published material; 2 folders (Box 84)
    - "The Image of Man's Greatness" San Francisco Sunday Examiner and Chronicle, Dec 1966; published material (Box 84)
    - "Inner Security Through Religion" The Wellesley Alumnae Magazine, Jul 1950; published material (Box 84)
    - "Key Piece in the Mideast Puzzle" New York Times Magazine, May 1957; preliminary drafts, typescript copy; final draft, typescript revised; galley fragment (rev.); published material; 4 folders (Box 84)